<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="6"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Historical Places in Pakistan









               Minar-e-Pakistan




               Minar-e-Pakistan (or Yadgaar-e-
               Pakistan) is a tall minaret in Iqbal Park
               Lahore, built in honor of the Lahore

               Resolution.


                     It reflects a blend of Mughal and
                       modern architecture, and is
                       constructed on the site where on
                       March 23, 1940, Lahore Resolution
                       (Qarardad-e-Lahore) demanding
                       the creation of Pakistan.  It was
                       seven years before the formation of
                       Pakistan.
                     The large public space around the
                       monument is commonly used for
                       political and public meetings,
                       whereas Iqbal Park area is ever so popular among kite-flyers.
                     The tower rises about 60 meters on the base, thus the total height of minaret
                       is about 62 meters above the ground.
                     The unfolding petals of the flower-like base are 9 meters high. The diameter
                       of the tower is about 97.5 meters (320 feet).]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Badshahi Mosque











































                     The Badshahi Mosque (Urdu: ﺪﺠﺴﻣ ﯽھﺎﺷدﺎﺑ), or the 'Emperor's Mosque', was

                       built in 1673 by the Mughal Emperor Aurangzeb in Lahore.
                       It is one of the city's best known landmarks, and a major tourist attraction
                       and characterizes the beauty and greatness of the Mughal era.

                     Capable of accommodating over 55,000 worshipers.
                     It is the second largest mosque in Pakistan, after the Faisal Mosque in
                       Islamabad.

                     The architecture and design of the Badshahi Masjid is closely related to the
                       Jama Masjid in Delhi, India, which was built in 1648 by Aurangzeb's father
                       and predecessor, Emperor Shah Jahan.

                     The Imam-e-Kaaba (Sheikh Abdur-Rahman Al-Sudais of Saudi Arabia) has
                       also led prayers in this mosque in 2007.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Mizar-e-Quaid



                     The Quaid-e-Azam`s Mausoleum is
                       a prominent and impressive

                       landmark of Karachi.


                     Nearby are the graves of the
                       “Quaid-e-Millat”.



                     Liaqat Ali Khan, the first Prime
                       Minister of Pakistan and the

                       Quaid`s sister, Mohtarma Fatima
                       Jinnah.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Faisal Mosque























                     The Shah Faisal Masjid in Islamabad, Pakistan, is among one of the largest

                       mosques in the world.  It is renowned for both its size and its architecture
                       covering an area of 5,000 square meters with a capacity of 300,000
                       worshippers.

                      Turkish architect Vedat Dalokay's designed it.
                     Construction of the mosque began in 1976 by National Construction of
                       Pakistan, led by Azim Borujerdi, and was funded by the government of

                       Saudi Arabia, at a cost of over 130 million Saudi riyals (approximately $120
                       million USD today).

                     It is located at the end of Shaharah-e-Islamabad, putting it at one end of the
                       city and in front of a magnificent backdrop provided by the Margalla Hills.
                     It is a focal point of Islamabad, and famous and recognized icon of the city.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Pakistan Monument








                                                                                       The National
                                                                                         Monument in
                                                                                         Islamabad,

                                                                                         Pakistan is a
                                                                                         national
                                                                                         monument
                                                                                         representing the

                                                                                         four provinces
                       and three territories of Pakistan.

                     Designed by Arif  Masood the blooming flower shape of the monument
                       represents Pakistan's progress as a rapidly developing country.
                     The four main petals of the monument represent the four provinces

                       (Balochistan, North West Frontier Province, Punjab, and Sindh), while the
                       three smaller petals represent the three territories (Northern Areas, Azad
                       Kashmir and the Federally Administered Tribal Areas).



                          The



                       Historical


                       Khyber Pass








                     The Khyber Pass, (Urdu:  ﮦرد
                       ﺮﺒﯿﺧ) t) is the mountain pass

                       that links Pakistan and
                       Afghanistan at an altitude of]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[1,070 m or 3,510 feet


                     Throughout history it has been an important trade route between Central
                       Asia and South Asia and a strategic military location.


                     The summit of the Khyber Pass is 5 kilometers (3.1 mi) inside Pakistan at

                       Landi Kotal and it cuts through the northeastern part of the White Mountains
                       or Koh-e-Safaid - extension of the Hindu Kush range.


                                                                               For centuries, it has been
                                                                                 a trade route between
                                                                                 south and north Asia.


                                                                               Every stone in the
                                                                                 Khyber has been soaked

                                                                                 in blood." Rudyard
                                                                                 Kipling called it "a
                                                                                 sword cut through the

                                                                                 mountains."]]></page></pages></Search>